<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on </title>
    <link>https://yumingfu.space/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>zn-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://yumingfu.space/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Xinhua News: Astronomers use LAMOST to find over 1,300 new quasars behind Galactic plane</title>
      <link>https://yumingfu.space/research/lamost-discovers-1300-new-gpqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yumingfu.space/research/lamost-discovers-1300-new-gpqs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BEIJING, April 18 (Xinhua) &amp;ndash; A group of astronomers has found over 1,300 new quasars behind the Galactic plane by using China&amp;rsquo;s Large Sky Area Multi-Object Fiber Spectroscopic Telescope (LAMOST), and the scientists said the results shed new light on some hot issues of cosmic research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://yumingfu.space/research/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yumingfu.space/research/publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A list of my publications can be found in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/search/q=orcid%3A0000-0002-0759-0504&amp;amp;sort=date+desc&#34;&gt;ADS library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-papers&#34;&gt;Selected papers:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yuming Fu&lt;/strong&gt;, Xue-Bing Wu, R. J. Bouwens, Karina I. Caputi, Yuxuan Pang, et al. “The&#xA;CatSouth Quasar Candidate Catalog for the Southern Sky and a Unified All-Sky Catalog&#xA;Based on Gaia DR3”. In: ApJS 279.2, 54 (Aug. 2025). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4365/ade999&#34;&gt;DOI: 10.3847/1538-4365/&#xA;ade999&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Interests</title>
      <link>https://yumingfu.space/research/research-interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yumingfu.space/research/research-interests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research fields include quasar surveys, statistical and machine learning methods in astronomy. My PhD thesis project was &amp;ldquo;Searching for Quasars behind the Galactic Plane&amp;rdquo;, aiming to select quasar candidates at |b| &amp;lt;= 20 deg with Machine Learning, and identify the candidates with optical telescopes. Currently, I am working in the OU-NIR and the Galaxy and AGN Evolution Science Working Group of the Euclid mission, focusing on NIR pipeline development and the quasar/AGN science in the Euclid survey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CatNorth Catalog: Over 1.5 Million Reliable Quasar Candidates from Gaia DR3</title>
      <link>https://yumingfu.space/research/catnorth-gaiadr3-quasar-candidate-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yumingfu.space/research/catnorth-gaiadr3-quasar-candidate-catalog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reposted from &lt;a href=&#34;https://kiaa.pku.edu.cn/info/1031/9270.htm&#34;&gt;KIAA-PKU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kavli Institute for Astronomy and Astrophysics at Peking University announces an advancement in cosmic exploration with the release of the CatNorth quasar candidate catalog, as recently published in The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series. The international collaborative study, led by Dr. Yuming Fu and Prof. Xue-Bing Wu, presents an enhanced set of over 1.5 million reliable quasar candidates, building upon the initial Gaia DR3 quasar candidate catalog noted for its substantial size but low purity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Featured Science: PKU Astronomers Discover Nearly 200 New Quasars behind the Galactic Plane</title>
      <link>https://yumingfu.space/research/200-new-quasars-behind-the-galactic-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 21:17:10 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yumingfu.space/research/200-new-quasars-behind-the-galactic-plane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are located at the edge of the Galactic disk, and see our Galaxy as a hazy band of light made of countless stars in the night sky. Looking for extragalactic objects like quasars through this band of light is so hard that this region has long been called the “Zone of Avoidance” for extragalactic astronomy. But now, a new research program makes it hard for quasars to hide themselves behind the Galactic plane.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Quasars behind the Galactic Plane</title>
      <link>https://yumingfu.space/research/finding_gpqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 12:59:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yumingfu.space/research/finding_gpqs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quasars behind the Galactic Plane (GPQs) are important astrometric references and useful probes of Milky Way gas, yet difficult to find. This project aims to select quasar candidates at |b| &amp;lt;= 20 deg with Machine Learning, and identify the candidates with optical telescopes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
